Alexander Bombicino

OFFICE 405 N Wabash Avenue Chicago, Illinois 60611

PHONE 312.321.9609

bombicino2@sbcglobal.net

March 13, 2013

appsFreedom 145 South 79th Street Chandler, AZ 85226

Dear Hiring Manager,

I'd like to apply for the Regional Enterprise Sales Executive position. In addition to meeting your requirements, I bring a unique perspective, determination and background to the role.

Listen. Learn. Deliver.

My career has been built on solving problems for customers. At its core, is understanding their underlying motivation, agenda and goals. The only way to truly solve problems is to listen to what prospects are saying and ask insightful, intelligent questions to help them define their needs.

Why Should You Consider Me For The Position?

- √ Having worked for several successful startup companies, I bring an assortment of knowledge and skill that only comes from experiencing dynamic and fast-paced environments first hand, where success is largely dependent on self-initiative and tenacity.
- ✓ Behind every enterprise solution and cloud based application is a relationship. Building these relationships across multiple levels, from C-level executives, to mid-level managers, to day-today users has always been a strength of mine.
- ✓ Complex solutions require a much different sales approach. You can't simply go in and sell on features and benefits. It's an acquired skill to approach sales as a trusted advisor working to create win-win scenarios for prospects and certainly a skill in which I've excelled.
- ✓ It's no surprise that I've been able to experience rapid new business acquisition and account growth throughout my career. Discipline plays an enormous role, as does the understanding that sales pipelines don't build themselves.
- ✓ A highly visible sales roles with extensive responsibility isn't for everyone. With the spotlight on you there's no one to blame if things don't go as planned. Having had success in the role several times, there's no greater reward or satisfaction. I thrive in such an environment.

I enjoy working in a dynamic environment with other motivated and talented individuals who enjoy making a difference while working together as a team. I welcome the opportunity to share more detail about my background and to learn more about the position.

Thank you for your time and consideration. I look forward to hearing from you.

Sincerely,

Alex Bombicino

Alex Bombicino

Sales Professional

Key Competencies

Sales

Enterprise software solutions Direct B2B sales Consultative approach Complex solution sell

Background

Startup company experience Large territory management Emerging markets Remote office success

Style

New business 'hunter' Relationship builder Needs-based analysis Disciplined approach

Channel

Channel recruitment Value-add partnering Distribution network alignment Reseller management

Management

Business plan development SE leadership Inside sales team direction Channel sales force oversight

Profile

Sales professional with proven track record selling complex software solutions into large and mid-range clients. Deep knowledge in enterprise solution sales and strategic selling. 'First-in' territory development, direct B2B sales and startup company experience.

Special Skills

New Technology Evangelist - proven success driving leading-edge solutions into emerging markets

Influencer - persuasive with the ability to articulate compelling value propositions based on client needs

Leadership - accomplished at winning mindshare and motivating others to action through example

Self-Starter - hard wired to take on challenges and responsibility for own success; driven, competitive

Accomplishments

Landed key \$3.5M marquee account for pre-IPO startup, win was instrumental in securing second round of VC funding.

Positioned service as key differentiator when competitors were focused on product, to win \$2M account that changed momentum within territory, ultimately leading to dominant market share.

Quickly ramped up sales operations growing regional revenues from \$0 to \$1.2M in less than 12 months.

Repeated success with another startup organization, taking first year revenues from \$0 to \$1.5M.

Instrumental in landing cornerstone account on newly launched software platform that was critical to establishing product credibility in role as sales lead for high-value strategic accounts.

Doggedly pursued prime account, even after decision was made to move forward with competitor, that ultimately led to reversal of decision and award of \$4M contract.

Regularly and consistently opened doors within Fortune 500 accounts to deliver six-figure sales.

Optimized target prospect existing partner relationships to win several multimillion-dollar accounts that otherwise would have taken years to develop, including one resulting in a breakthrough \$2M win.

Experience

North American Territory Manager, ClearShield Technologies; Chicago, IL - 2011-2013

Sales Consultant, Applied Systems; Chicago, IL – 2008-2011 'Chicago's Largest Revenue Private Companies' – Crain's 2009

Regional Sales Manager, Scriptlogic; Chicago, IL – 2004-2008 '500 Fastest Growing Technology Companies' – Deloitte 2005

Regional Sales Representative, @pos.com / Symbol; Chicago, IL – 1997-2004 'Silicon Valley Fast 50' – Deloitte 2000

Territory Manager, Racal; Chicago, IL - 1994-1997

Account Executive, PageNet; Chicago, IL - 1990-1994

Education

Northern Illinois University; DeKalb, IL - B.S. Marketing 1987